Inventory of Civil registers of actions from District Court (Fifth District: Washington County), 1896-1990.
Utah State Archives and Records Service
District Court (Fifth District: Washington County) Civil registers of actions
1896-1990.
Utah State Archives and Records Service 300 South Rio Grande Salt Lake City, UT 84101-1182 801-533-3535 historyresearch@utah.gov
Series 18193
District Court (Fifth District: Washington County)
12.00 cubic feet and 29 microfilm reels
The register of action for the Washington County Fifth District court contains entries pertaining to civil cases and assists with tracking documents filed for each case.
Historical Note
An agency history is available.
Civil cases document the legal process and the administration of justice in conjunction with civil proceedings for the determination of a controversy between parties wherein rights are enforced or protected, or wrongs are prevented or redressed. Records and documents pertaining to a particular civil action are filed together by the court clerk and collectively these documents constitute the case file. As these records or actions are filed, the clerk enters them in the registers which comprise this series. The clerk is required as documents enter the case file to make a notation that shows "the nature of each paper filed or writ issued and the substance of each order or judgment of the court and of the returns showing execution of process. The notation of an order or judgment shall show the date the notation is made. When trial by jury has been properly demanded or ordered the clerk shall enter the word 'jury' on the page assigned to that action" [UCA 79 (b) (2)].
A register of actions may contain the following entries for each civil case: name of the attorney for plaintiff and defendant, name of the judge presiding over the case, petitions, complaints, summons, answers to summons, orders from the court, assignment of judges, exhibits, judgment, findings and conclusions, costs, decrees, requests by attorneys for instructions to the jury, verdict, motions for cross complaints or new trials, amendments to previous answers and disclaimers.
Numerical by case number, thereunder chronological
This series is classified as Public.
These records were acquired from the creating agency through established retention schedules.
Indexes: An alphabetical index is located at the beginning of each register.
Civil case files from the District Court (Fifth District: Washington County), Series 3635, contains the entire case file listed in these registers.
Register of actions from the District Court (Fifth District: Washington County), Series 23737, include civil cases as well.
Index to civil and criminal actions from the District Court (Fifth District: Washington County), Series 26247, provide specific dates for actions in the cases cited in this index.
Politics, Government, and Law; Civil Procedure and Courts
Court records--Washington County (Utah).; Divorce suits--Washington County (Utah).
Washington County (Utah)--Trials.
- Civil registers of actions, 1896-1990.; 12.00 cubic feet and 29 microfilm reels
  - 1-349, 1896-1928 (Reel 1, Volume 1)
  - 351-748, 1925-1934 (Reel 1, Volume A)
  - 749-1150, 1934-1939 (Reel 2, Volume B)
  - 1155-1754, 1939-1949 (Reel 3, Volume C)
  - 1755-2354, 1949-1955 (Reel 4, Volume D)
  - 2355-2954, 1955-1961 (Reel 3, Volume E)
  - 2955-3554, 1961-1966 (Reel 5, Volume F)
  - 3555-4154, 1966-1969 (Reel 5, Volume G)
  - 4155-4754, 1969-1972 (Reel 6, Volume H)
  - 4755-5354, 1972-1974 (Reel 7, Volume I)
  - 5355-5954, 1974-1975 (Reel 8, Volume J)
  - 5955-6554, 1976-1977 (Reel 9, Volume K)
  - 6555-7154, 1977-1979 (Reel 10, Volume L)
  - 7155-7754, 1979-1984 (Reel 11, Volume M)
  - 7755-8354, 1980-1982 (Reel 12, Volume N)
  - 8355-8954, 1982-1983 (Reel 13, Volume O)
  - 8955-9554, 1983-1984 (Reel 14, Volume P)
  - 9555-10154, 1984-1985 (Reel 15, Volume Q)
  - 85:001-85:600, 1985 (Reel 16, Volume R)
  - 86:601-86:1200, 1986 (Reel 17, Volume S)
  - 87:1201-87:1800, 1987 (Reel 18, Volume T)
  - 88:1801-88:2400, 1988 (Reel 19, Volume U)
  - 89:2401-89:3000, 1989 (Reel 20, Volume V)
  - 90:3001-90:3600, 1990 (Reel 21, Volume W)